Guide to the Paul Hindemith Oral History Collection
Paul Hindemith Oral History
Oral History of American Music
Paul Hindemith Oral History
1951 2007
1972 1977
OHI
Oral History of American Music
185 Computer Files
General
79 interviews as of September 9, 2021. This finding aid describes digitized copies of the interview recordings in this collection. Oral History of American Music also holds the original recordings, on a variety of legacy audio and video formats.
Scope and Contents
The Paul Hindemith Oral History consists of seventy-nine interviews with students, performers, colleagues, and friends of the celebrated German composer. The Hindemith oral history complements and gives added dimension to the Paul Hindemith Collection of personal papers and manuscripts in the Irving S. Gilmore Music Library at Yale University.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. The finding aid includes links to stream most interviews online via Oral History of American Music's (OHAM) AV access system, Aviary. Yale users can login to Aviary using their Yale University ID, to stream these interviews without restriction. Other users are able to request access to interviews directly through Aviary. For access instructions, and to request transcripts of an interview, see OHAM's website. This finding aid also includes links to Table of Contents for most interviews.
Some interviews may be restricted. Access to these restricted interviews may only be granted to a patron who has first obtained direct permission from the interviewee or their estate.
Some interviews may not have been digitized or are otherwise not available to stream online. However, these interviews may have been transcribed. Please see contact OHAM for more details.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by surname of interviewee.
Related Collection
MSS 47, The Paul Hindemith Collection.
Composers United States 20th Century; Composers Germany; Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963
- Adler, Samuel
  - Adler, Samuel, 1975 November 11 1975 November 11; OHI 30 37 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 22 pages; Approximate Running Time: 40 minutes
    Interview Location
    Fort Worth, TX
    Interviewee Discusses
    Paul Hindemith
    Adler, Samuel, 1928-
- Bartholomew, Marshall
  - Bartholomew, Marshall, 1975 May 30 1975 May 30; OHI 30 30 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 22 pages; Approximate Running Time: 59 minutes
    Branford, CT
    Bartholomew, Marshall, 1885-1978
- Bauer, Phyllis
  - Bauer, Phyllis [TEST], 1975 May 7 1975 May 7; OHI 30 28 a-c; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 66 pages; Approximate Running Time: 114 minutes
    Bronx, NY
    Bauer, Phyllis
- Boatwright, Howard
  - Boatwright, Howard, 1976 December 16 1976 December 16; OHI 30 73 a-f; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 107 pages; Approximate Running Time: 236 minutes
    Fayetteville, NY
    Boatwright, Helen
- Bonaventura, Sam di
  - Bonaventura, Sam di, 1976 April 5 1976 April 5; OHI 30 43 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 63 pages; Approximate Running Time: 84 minutes
    Fairfax, VA
    Di Bonaventura, Sam
- Boykan, Martin
  - Boykan, Martin, 1976 April 25 1976 April 25; OHI 30 54 a-c; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 55 pages; Approximate Running Time: 135 minutes
    Newton, MA
    Boykan, Martin, 1931-
- Bozyan, Mrs. Frank
  - Bozyan, Mrs. Frank, 1973 March 1 1973 March 1; OHI 30 4 a; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 20 pages; Approximate Running Time: 31 minutes
    3283 Morse College
    Boyzan, Margaret Bliss, 1901-1998
- Calhoun, Robert L. and Mrs.
  - Calhoun, Robert L. and Mrs., 1973 June 6 1973 June 6; OHI 30_8 a_b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 22 pages; Approximate Running Time: 52 minutes
    Bethany, CT
    Calhoun, Robert Lowry, 1896-1983; Calhoun, Ella Clay Wakeman, 1893-1985
- Cannon, Beekman
  - Cannon, Beekman, 1976 April 22 1976 April 22; OHI 30 51 a-c; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 33 pages; Approximate Running Time: 85 minutes
    New Haven, CT
    Cannon, Beekman Cox, 1911-2004
- Colman, John
  - Colman, John, 1976 November 21 1976 November 21; OHI 30 70 a-d; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 76 pages; Approximate Running Time: 145 minutes
    New York, NY
    Colman, John, 1913-
- Crosby, John
  - Crosby, John, 1976 November 22 1976 November 22; OHI 30 71 a; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 14 pages; Approximate Running Time: 31 minutes
    Crosby, John, 1926-2002
- Currier, Donald
  - Currier, Donald, 1973 June 22 1973 June 22; OHI 30 9 a; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 18 pages; Approximate Running Time: 39 minutes
    Currier, Donald
- Davenny, Ward
  - Davenny, Ward, 1975 June 3 1975 June 3; OHI 30 31 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 30 pages; Approximate Running Time: 61 minutes
    Davenny, Ward, 1951-
- De Witt, Isabel
  - De Witt, Isabel, 1975 January 21 1975 January 21; OHI 30 14 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 26 pages; Approximate Running Time: 62 minutes
    De Witt, Isabel
- Dello Joio, Norman
  - Dello Joio, Norman, 1976 April 26 1976 April 26; OHI 30 55 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 33 pages; Approximate Running Time: 52 minutes
    Boston, MA
    Dello Joio, Norman, 1913-2008
- Doob, Leonard
  - Doob, Leonard, 1975 March 10 1975 March 10; OHI 30 20 a; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 16 pages; Approximate Running Time: 29 minutes
    Doob, Leonard W. (Leonard William), 1909-2000
- Dorati, Antal
  - Dorati, Antal, 1976 November 8 1976 November 8; OHI 30 62 a; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 9 pages; Approximate Running Time: 11 minutes
    Washington, DC
    Dorati, Antal
- Feist, Leonard
  - Feist, Leonard, 1976 November 16 1976 November 16; OHI 30 67 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 26 pages; Approximate Running Time: 62 minutes
    Feist, Leonard, 1910-1996
- Foss, Lukas
  - Foss, Lukas, 1976 November 11 1976 November 11; OHI 30 64 a; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 30 pages; Approximate Running Time: 45 minutes
    Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009
- French, Richard
  - French, Richard, 1975 February 7 1975 February 7; OHI 30 17 a-d; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 59 pages; Approximate Running Time: 104 minutes
    French, Richard F. (Richard Frederic), 1915-2001
- Fromm, Herbert
  - Fromm, Herbert, 1977 January 5 1977 January 5; OHI 30 75 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 42 pages; Approximate Running Time: 88 minutes
    Brookline, MA
    Fromm, Herbert, 1905-
- Frost, Thomas
  - Frost, Thomas, 1976 April 12 1976 April 12; OHI 30 47 a-c; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 20 pages; Approximate Running Time: 74 minutes
    Frost, Thomas
- Grubb, Margaret
  - Grubb, Margaret, 1976 January 17 1976 January 17; OHI 30 40 a-d; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 72 pages; Approximate Running Time: 121 minutes
    Interviewer
    Caitriona Bolster
    Denton, TX
    Grubb, Margaret
- Grumman, S. Ellsworth
  - Grumman, S. Ellsworth, 1972 December 14 1972 December 14; OHI 30 7 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 30 pages; Approximate Running Time: 63 minutes
    Grumman, S. Ellsworth
- Grumman, S. Ellsworth and Mrs.
  - Grumman, S. Ellsworth and Mrs., 1973 January 23 1973 January 23; OHI 30 7 c-d; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 25 pages; Approximate Running Time: 64 minutes
    Grumman, Carol L. Sterling, 1891-1986; Grumman, S. Ellsworth
- Hague, Mrs. Arthur
  - Hague, Mrs. Arthur, undated; OHI 30 29 a; Bolster, Caitriona; Approximate Running Time: 36 minutes
    Not Available
    Hague, Marjory Abbott
- Hart, Margaret Grady
  - Hart, Margaret Grady, 1976 April 28 1976 April 28; OHI 30 57 a-c; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 62 pages; Approximate Running Time: 126 minutes
    Hart, Margaret Grady
- Heath, Fenno
  - Heath, Fenno, 1975 January 16 1975 January 16; OHI 30 13 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 38 pages; Approximate Running Time: 57 minutes
    Heath, Fenno, 1926-2008
- Hemingway, Louis
  - Hemingway, Louis, 1973 March 21 1973 March 21; OHI 30 5 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 29 pages; Approximate Running Time: 61 minutes
    Hemingway, Louis
- Hickok, Robert
  - Hickok, Robert, 1976 April 7 1976 April 7; OHI 30 44 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 48 pages; Approximate Running Time: 87 minutes
    Brooklyn, NY
    Hickok, Robert
- Hindemith, Paul
  - Hindemith, Paul, 1951 1951; OHI 30 a; Approximate Running Time: 21 minutes
    Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963
- Iadone, Joseph
  - Iadone, Joseph, 1975 April 13 1975 April 13; OHI 30 25 a-c; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 55 pages; Approximate Running Time: 104 minutes
    Bridgeport, CT
    Iadone, Joseph
- Jacobson, George
  - Jacobson, George, 1973 April 19 1973 April 19; OHI 30 6 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 34 pages; Approximate Running Time: 64 minutes
    Jacobson, George
- Kaufmann, Henry
  - Kaufmann, Henry, 1976 November 19 1976 November 19; OHI 30 69 a-d; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 65 pages; Approximate Running Time: 129 minutes
    New Brunswick, NJ
    Kaufmann, Henry W. (Henry William), 1913-1982
- Kay, Ulysses
  - Kay, Ulysses, 1976 April 8 1976 April 8; OHI 30 45 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 43 pages; Approximate Running Time: 76 minutes
    Kay, Ulysees, 1917-1995
- Kirkpatrick, Ralph
  - Kirkpatrick, Ralph, 1975 March 11 1975 March 11; OHI 30 24 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 33 pages; Approximate Running Time: 82 minutes
    Kirkpatrick, Ralph, 1911-1984
- Kraehenbuehl, David
  - Kraehenbuehl, David, 1976 April 9 1976 April 9; OHI 30 46 a-g; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 159 pages; Approximate Running Time: 217 minutes
    Princeton Junction, NJ
    Kraehenbuehl, David
- Leigh, Mitch
  - Leigh, Mitch, 1976 November 17 1976 November 17; OHI 30 68 a-c; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 37 pages; Approximate Running Time: 72 minutes
    Leigh, Mitch, 1928-2014
- Levine, Maurice
  - Levine, Maurice, 1975 June 24 1975 June 24; OHI 30 35 a-c; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 64 pages; Approximate Running Time: 103 minutes
    Levine, Maurice
- Lewin, Frank
  - Lewin, Frank, 1975 December 13 1975 December 13; OHI 30 19 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 38 pages; Approximate Running Time: 60 minutes
    Lewin, Frank
  - Lewin, Frank, 2007 February 9 2007 February 9; OHI 30 19 c-d; Pavese, Frank; Approximate Running Time: 99 minutes
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Frank Lewin
    LSF
- Lieberson, Goddard
  - Lieberson, Goddard, 1975 April 10 1975 April 10; OHI 30 26 a; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 15 pages; Approximate Running Time: 28 minutes
    Lieberson, Goddard, 1911-1977
- Liepmann, Klaus
  - Liepmann, Klaus, 1976 April 27 1976 April 27; OHI 30 56 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 34 pages; Approximate Running Time: 79 minutes
    Cambridge, MA
    Liepmann, Klaus
- Loach, Donald
  - Loach, Donald, 1976 April 4 1976 April 4; OHI 30 42 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 49 pages; Approximate Running Time: 89 minutes
    Charlottesville, VA
    Loach, Donald
- London, George
  - London, George, 1976 November 5 1976 November 5; OHI 30 61 a; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 11 pages; Approximate Running Time: 19 minutes
    Washington, D.C.
    London, George, 1920-1985
- Lowe, Gretel
  - Lowe, Gretel, 1973 November 28 1973 November 28; OHI 30 10 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 45 pages; Approximate Running Time: 87 minutes
    Hamden, CT
    Lowe, Gretel
- Mainous, Jean
  - Mainous, Jean, 1976 January 11 1976 January 11; OHI 30 39 a-c; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 45 pages; Approximate Running Time: 84 minutes
    Mainous, Jean
- Martens, Mason
  - Martens, Mason, 1975 June 4 1975 June 4; OHI 30 33 a-f; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 135 pages; Approximate Running Time: 231 minutes
    Martens, Mason
- Maynard, Paul
  - Maynard, Paul, 1976 November 15 1976 November 15; OHI 30 65 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 43 pages; Approximate Running Time: 81 minutes
    Bayside, NY
    Maynard, Paul
- Mendel, Arthur
  - Mendel, Arthur, 1976 April 21 1976 April 21; OHI 30 50 a-c; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 57 pages; Approximate Running Time: 96 minutes
    Princeton, NJ
    Mendel, Arthur, 1905-1979
- Miller, Carl
  - Miller, Carl, 1975 February 4 1975 February 4; OHI 30 16 a-d; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 59 pages; Approximate Running Time: 192 minutes
    Miller, Carl
  - Miller, Carl, 1975 March 25 1975 March 25; OHI 30 16 e-f; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 28 pages; Approximate Running Time: 192 minutes
- Myer, Jean
  - Myer, Jean, 1976 November 4 1976 November 4; OHI 30 60 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 45 pages; Approximate Running Time: 93 minutes
    Bethany Beach, DE
    Myer, Jean
- Noss, Osea
  - Noss, Osea, 1973 May 9 1973 May 9; OHI 30 2 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 29 pages; Approximate Running Time: 67 minutes
    Noss, Osea
- Noss, Luther
  - Noss, Luther, 1973 March 20 1973 March 20; OHI 30 1 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Approximate Running Time: 62 minutes
    Yale Univ.
    Noss, Luther, 1907-1995
- O'Meara, Eva Judd
  - O'Meara, Eva Judd, 1973 February 1 1973 February 1; OHI 30 3 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 15 pages; Approximate Running Time: 47 minutes
    O'Meara, Eva Judd, 1884-1979
- Parisot, Aldo
  - Parisot, Aldo, 1976 April 16 1976 April 16; OHI 30 48 a; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 24 pages; Approximate Running Time: 36 minutes
    Parisot, Aldo, 1921-
- Pearson, Norman
  - Pearson, Norman, 1973 December 6 1973 December 6; OHI 30 11 a; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 17 pages; Approximate Running Time: 38 minutes
    Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1909-1975
- Peyre, Henri
  - Peyre, Henri, 1975 February 7 1975 February 7; OHI 30 18 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 31 pages; Approximate Running Time: 49 minutes
    Peyre, Henri, 1901-1988
- Pisk, Paul
  - Pisk, Paul, 1976 November 1976 November; OHI 30 72 a; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 4 pages; Approximate Running Time: 10 minutes
    Pisk, Paul Amadeus, 1893-1990
- Powell, Mel
  - Powell, Mel, 1976 August 19 1976 August 19; OHI 30 58 a-f; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 97 pages; Approximate Running Time: 261 minutes
    Northridge, CA
    Powell, Mel, 1923-1998
- Reutter, Hermann
  - Reutter, Hermann, 1976 March 26 1976 March 26; OHI 30 49 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 31 pages; Approximate Running Time: 63 minutes
    Reutter, Hermann, 1900-1985
- Richter, Eckhart
  - Richter, Eckhart, 1975 December 29 1975 December 29; OHI 30 38 a-d; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 70 pages; Approximate Running Time: 142 minutes
    Atlanta, GA
    Richter, Eckhart
- Ross, Hugh
  - Ross, Hugh, 1976 November 15 1976 November 15; OHI 30 66 a; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 18 pages; Approximate Running Time: 28 minutes
    Ross Williamson, Hugh, 1901-1978
- Ruff, Willie
  - Ruff, Willie, 1975 January 27 1975 January 27; OHI 30 15 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 34 pages; Approximate Running Time: 68 minutes
    Scope and Contents
    Ruff, Willie
- Saranec, Edmund
  - Saranec, Edmund, 1975 March 17 1975 March 17; OHI 30 21 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 21 pages; Approximate Running Time: 39 minutes
    Saranec, Edmund
- Schnabel, Karl Ulrich
  - Schnabel, Karl Ulrich, 1976 December 18 1976 December 18; OHI 30 74 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 23 pages; Approximate Running Time: 43 minutes
    Schnabel, Karl Ulrich
- Schonthal-Seckel, Ruth
  - Schonthal-Seckel, Ruth, 1974 January 24 1974 January 24; OHI 30 12 a; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 22 pages; Approximate Running Time: 39 minutes
    Schonthal-Seckel, Ruth
- Shapero, Harold
  - Shapero, Harold, 1976 April 24 1976 April 24; OHI 30 53 a-c; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 85 pages; Approximate Running Time: 118 minutes
    Natrick, MA
    Shapero, Harold, 1920-2013
- Shaw, Robert
  - Shaw, Robert, 1976 April 3 1976 April 3; OHI 30 41 a-c; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 38 pages; Approximate Running Time: 79 minutes
- Simonds, Bruce and Rosalind
  - Simonds, Bruce and Rosalind, 1976 April 22 1976 April 22; OHI 30 52 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 49 pages; Approximate Running Time: 60 minutes
    Simonds, Bruce; Simonds, Rosalind Brown
- Stone, Kurt
  - Stone, Kurt, 1975 June 4 1975 June 4; OHI 30 32 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 52 pages; Approximate Running Time: 94 minutes
    Stone, Kurt
- Strauss, John
  - Strauss, John, 1975 June 24 1975 June 24; OHI 30 36 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 53 pages; Approximate Running Time: 88 minutes
    Strauss, John, 1920-2011
- Truax (Reese*), Carol
  - Truax (Reese*), Carol, 1976 November 10 1976 November 10; OHI 30 63 a; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 27 pages; Approximate Running Time: 28 minutes
    Truax, Carol
- Waite, William
  - Waite, William, 1975 April 10 1975 April 10; OHI 30 23 a; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 14 pages; Approximate Running Time: 30 minutes
    Waite, William G.
- Wilson, Keith
  - Wilson, Keith, 1975 March 20 1975 March 20; OHI 30 22 a-b; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 21 pages; Approximate Running Time: 53 minutes
    Wilson, Keith L. (Keith Leroy), 1916-2013
- Wimsatt, Margaret
  - Wimsatt, Margaret, 1975 April 14 1975 April 14; OHI 30 27 a; Bolster, Caitriona; Approximate Running Time: 9 minutes
    Wimsatt, Margaret Hecht, 1919-1999
- Woldt, John
  - Woldt, John, 1976 October 13 1976 October 13; OHI 30 59 a-d; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 69 pages; Approximate Running Time: 147 minutes
    Woldt, John
- Wyner, Yehudi
  - Wyner, Yehudi, 1975 June 18 1975 June 18; OHI 30 34 a-d; Bolster, Caitriona; Transcript Page Count: 77 pages; Approximate Running Time: 143 minutes
    Wyner, Yehudi, 1929-